le.ac.uk 2016-05-29

# Privacy policy — University of Leicester

The University of Leicester acknowledges that personal privacy is a very important issue. We support the protection of internet privacy as required under UK legislation.

The statement on this web page explains the types of personal information which are collected when you visit our website and how this will be used. Please note that this policy only applies to University of Leicester web pages, ie. those within the le.ac.uk domain.

## Personal information

Any personal information which you provide via the website, such as your name and address, will only be used only for the specific purpose stated. We will never sell, trade or license this information to other parties. We never provide website users’ personal information to direct marketing companies or similar organisations.

### Submission forms and surveys

The University of Leicester may also collect personal information supplied through the use of web-based forms and surveys. This information will not be supplied to any third party, and will only be used for subsequent communications, if indicated by you, the user, at the time of submission.

In submitting your personal information online, you are agreeing that University staff may use your details for the sole purpose of conducting the business of the University. If at anytime you no longer wish to receive any information from the University of Leicester, please respond to any email and state that you wish to “unsubscribe” or click on our unsubscribe links in emails.

## Authentication

Some parts of our website are only accessible to University of Leicester staff and students who can log in using their standard university username and password. This secure access system uses cookies but these cookies are used only for identification and not for any other purpose; the cookies are deleted when each session ends. Logs are kept of the date/time/user ID of all log-in sessions, and these may be used for diagnostic or problem-solving purposes.

## Credit card payments

Credit card payments can be made through our online shop, shop@le which has its own separate terms and conditions.

## Activity Logs

Our systems automatically record all requests for accessing web content, including the requesting computer’s IP address. This is a standard function of web serving technology and, as above, we only use these logs for diagnostic and problem-solving purposes.

## Cookies

To identify which webpages are accessed, we use traffic log cookies and analytics services provided by Crazy Egg and Google. From this we can analyse data about web traffic and thereby constantly improve our website for users. This information is only used for statistical analysis. Cookies help the University to provide you the website visitor with a better service by enabling us to identify which pages are most useful to most people.

Cookies do not give us access to your computer and do not reveal any information other than whatever data you choose to share with us via webforms or other inputs. Web browsers are usually set to accept all cookies automatically, but you can modify your browser to decline or query cookies.

By using the University of Leicester website, you give your consent for us to process the data you provide in the manner and for the purposes described above. Find out more about cookies at [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)

#### Please Note:

Third party vendors, including Google, show our ads on sites on the internet.   
Third party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on a user's prior visits to our website.   
Users may opt out of Google's use of cookies by visiting the Google [advertising opt-out page](http://www.google.com/privacy/ads/).  
Crazy Egg provides a [page with details for blocking cookies](http://www.crazyegg.com/opt-out)

## Monitoring and Disclosure

Please note that in certain circumstances the University of Leicester may be obliged to disclose information or undertake more detailed monitoring under the [Regulation of Investigatory Powers Act 2000](http://www.legislation.gov.uk/ukpga/2000/23/contents).
